let's talk about what makes um somebody a capitalist what makes us because i think we we
we're failing to understand you know that there's gonna have to be there's gonna have to be a bridge
built right like if you if you live in a capitalist society if you live in capitalism
then and the goal is to get out of it right there's gonna have to be a bridge built can
we agree on that hey miss debbie so we can agree on that so okay so people agree on that right
so you know i still have a lot to learn about communism right so i can't i can't say um hey
i can't say that i'm a communist yet because i just haven't learned enough i'm in i'm in a learning
process right now i'm in a learning process so i can't say i'm a communist yet um what i will say
though is that i am an artist and i create ip hey paul so as somebody who creates intellectual property
there is something very unique to what i make and that is different than perhaps maybe um a necessity
like like you know having access to water housing etc and there's also um something different in
service right like there would be services that are required now don't get me wrong you got some
people that are better at doing other services that better at doing services than others like i know
something that a barber was telling me in cuba was that it was frustrating for him under communism
because he was like i gotta get the same rate as another cop as another barber even though i'm a
better barber right um and so you know i can understand that how like these nuances can can get
in the way of necessarily like a complete vision of something um as a system taking taking place right
um you know at the end of the day communism is the people owning the means of production
so that's really what communism is at the end of the day now where we are right now is in a
completely capitalist society that's only getting even further capitalist right so by that i say that
it's getting privatized but what i want to talk about is that there is a reality that certain spaces are
choosing in their capitalism um that doesn't have to be the case there is a failure to build a bridge
by nature of having a solely capitalist mindset okay so
the idea that a bookstore would only exist for the purpose of selling books is is not that to me is
a failure to build a bridge particularly a black bookstore the idea that a black artist
would solely exist would solely exist to make money off their art is completely capitalist to me that's
nonsensical because ultimately our art serves a means for us to have a livelihood as well as serving as
a means to improve the lives of our people so there has to be a symbiosis there there has to be a consciousness
around that so for instance i do my best to provide free shows
where there are opportunities there to support my work
right so like i will do free shows where you can also get a meet and greet or you can buy merch etc
so that is to me a way for me as an artist to exist completely wholly in my art as well as
completely wholly in my effort to be an integral part of my community's empowerment enrichment and education
but that was a conscious decision that i had to make
okay like i had to consciously divest from celebrity i had to consciously divest from these spaces that
only think in that way also because the people around you only think in that way so for instance like
i am this is my book what would the ancestors say i will be selling this book only via my
means of selling aside from any independent stores that choose to buy from me but i will not be selling it
via the mass um corporation means of production whether that's target or barns or x or amazon etc
now that is not solely because i feel like i should possess all of the sales but that's also because
as a creator if i am in putting my product in their um machine i am feeding their machine
so i don't want to feed their machine okay i don't want to feed their machine
and someone here said be careful someone made copies of my sister's book and was famous
and sold it themselves um i don't know what that means but if someone made copies of my book
and uh sold it i mean that's just like the kind of that's just where we are
like there's no way for me to prevent that like even as you say that there is no way to prevent that
hey eric y'all say hi to fine ass eric and congratulate him on having a new child better
y'all than me better y'all than me i'm not making babies i'm making books um
so yeah okay so like people are like well what about a copyright of course you have a copyright
in order to um enforce a copyright you have to sue
you have to send them a cease and desist and then if they don't cease and desist you have
to sue that is the con that that that is the the world the nation that we live in it is a litigious
nation right and we don't have a nation that is less that is necessarily built on the honor system
like that's not that's not culturally how we exist okay so when i when i say to you ask yourselves
am i a capitalist um we we we have to ask ourselves in what scenarios am i solely thinking
of capital gain and how do i apply it so like when i sell my art when i sell my pins and my paper
goods etc i do make capital off of that i also spend capital to make it the uniqueness about
these scenarios i mean about these items though is that they are not items of necessity
right i'm not selling you food i'm not selling you water i'm not even selling you clothes i may sell
you t-shirts okay but i'm not selling you housing i'm not selling you heat
in the winter i'm not selling you electricity i'm not selling you means for living i'm not selling
you health care i'm not selling you women's hygiene i'm selling you novelty items that are effective
that i hope are effective in providing education edutainment uh empowerment etc however they are a choice
they are a want now someone here said it's knowledge though i also provide free knowledge
oh someone said okay love get to the point okay go fuck yourself how about that if you can't see the
point and you tell me to get to the point you can get the fuck on i don't know who y'all think you're
talking to i genuinely be don't i i really genuinely don't be knowing who y'all think you're talking to
because if that nigga said that to me in person i will black if that nigga said that to me in person i
will black out i thought i blocked you get out of here wasn't meant to be disrespectful who do y'all
who raised y'all you got gray in your beard you don't know how that's disrespectful okay okay
so i also hate when i'm in flow and motherfuckers be like like that'd be driving me nutty as i said
when it comes to the concept of am i a capitalist the concept of capitalism is um
exploitation and a false sense of scarcity so capitalism suggests that there is less of
something than there actually is and then provides a higher rate based on it
a layer in miami said when her accent changes it's about to be on some ish that's that is correct
that is correct um so when um i have had to ask myself i'm wrong how am i wrong how am i wrong
they didn't pay me to tell you what lipstick this is now see some might say you're being capitalist no
what i am being is aware of my worth because a company that i paid to wear this did not pay me
to endorse it and i know that me endorsing something has value and in a nation of corporations
i am not gonna be used thank you so this is my book i will be on here every night talking about
this book i'll be doing a live stream performance and book release on november 8th and i am so proud of
this piece of work because not only did i write it not only did i do the designs i laid it out myself
okay i sat up and learned in design so i could lay it out myself and i cannot tell you how proud i am
that i did this and um there's some changes i'm gonna make before it's available but someone said is
tupac an ancestor you better know thank you kill a candy 27 it's so pretty like it's an actual like
pretty book yes yasmine it will be available in europe um so i was supposed to drop my memoir
on november 4th through simon and schuster
and i chose to not drop my book i paid 75 000 to simon schuster to simon and schuster i gave them
back their advance i gave them back their advance in order to own my memoir and i know some of y'all
might be thinking damn she must have money that was the money and i gave it back and then i
said you know what that memoir is not the that's not the work for this time
and so i decided to put this on paper and i had been performing it on stage just through my mind and
and in improvisation but i decided to sit down and write it so i sat down and wrote it and um and then
laid it out and did the and did the designs etc and i had been doing that so i was writing my book from
my memoir from february of 2024 till may of i turned it in on may 3rd 2025 and then i started writing this
um on in july and so it is going to drop on november 8th so it is still within the same timeline
and it will be available for purchase on november 8th and you'll be able to purchase uh the book
by itself you'll be able to purchase a ticket so the tickets to my one woman show will be available
before before then um however i just want you all to know that when you're supporting my work you are
supporting someone that does not think as a capitalist there's a reason why i do views from
amanda land every wednesday and it is free it is not behind the paywall there's a reason why it's
also available as a podcast there's a reason why i'm creating a children's show that will also be
available for free there's a reason why my podcast small doses which has been in existence for eight
years was also free there's a reason why i came back to instagram and it's because the title is what
would the ancestors say and it's because i understand the necessity for interaction for education for other
perspectives insights like i am one of many who are here doing this i'm the most misunderstood
person on the net because i have pivoted most people have only existed in one form and so people
only know them as that i came into the internet as an actress on a tv show and people have only seen
me in certain mindsets i came on the internet and was positioned by black spaces as a villain whether that be
um hollywood unlocked or shade room or neighborhood talk all of these spaces have prevent presented me
as a villain right making the consistent choice to not consistently show me as a truth teller
and even if there are things that people would disagree with they they purposely only post things
that they consider incendiary right so a lot of people on the internet only know me within a very
very very very specific context because that is where they get their content from and those places have a
very narrow positioning of me things change and it's been very beautiful to see people you know who are
curious um be willing to expand their consciousness and their perspectives and then say oh i'm i actually
understand what she's talking about damn um i should actually hear from her versus from other people
repurposing her content or her quotes etc etc um and you know that's it
also like i was on the insecure i was on insecure and like i was like the light-skinned bougie friend
which even though after season one i wasn't like throwing shade to my co-stars i like in the in the
showing throwing shade to the other characters like they had written me as in season one
um it was still like oh she's the light-skinned bougie one so literally just existing as the light can
light-skinned bougie one in that context made me the villain like they weren't even writing the
character that way anymore i was still the villain someone said is it difficult to go from
the intellectual to a comedian no because many comedians are intellectual george carlin
like i can name davidson boswell like i can go on and on and on about intellectual comedians
dave chapelle chris rock these are intellectual comedians you know so um i say all of that to say
that i think it's important to ask yourself where does um where does the capitalism exist within you
right and how much of it is a choice and how much of it is a indoctrination that's just habit
and then you have to work your way back from that you know you got to work your way back from that
why it's an act intellectual comedian thank you lisa
lisa said absolutely not lisa said misunderstood person on the net people definitely understand
you the dusty bums are gaslighting you because you're over two million followers love you
thank you lisa so yeah someone just said yeah where does the capitalism exist within you
right and part of this is also doing the learning of what is socialism right like what is this concept
and anything that the u.s government has vilified you should make it your business to look into so cuba
russia socialism capitalism leftism anything that the u.s government vilifies
you should make it your business to learn about north korea it is not to say that there won't be
factors in there that make you go yeah i don't agree with that however you cannot trust this nation's
framing of anything as just honest or fair actually i'm gonna take out fair just
honest honest honest or conclusive you have to do your own research you have a country venezuela you got
this nation right now trying to tell you that venezuela is a communist country that is selling drugs first of
all none of all none of that makes sense however the only way you really get to understand how these spaces
work is to learn from hearing about it from people that actually live there listening to their scholars
looking at their independent press all of these countries have mainstream media you have to look at their independent press
okay so again ask yourself where does the capitalism exist within me when i have a black bookstore
tell me we will not have you as a book signer we will not have you in our store signing your books
unless we get a cut of your books that is contradictory to me of the necessity for black bookstores to be
spaces of community and elevation for black intellectualism there was somebody in the comments who said as a
bookstore owner i understand it doesn't make sense for me to host a book signing if i don't make money off the books
you're right if capitalism is your only goal however if the book seller is an independent seller that is selling their own
books then there is no reason unless you have additional costs associated with them doing a signing there is no reason
there is no reason why you would not invite them into your space to sell their book that elevates and
educates and and empowers black people that is a completely relevant reason why you would have someone there
so here someone says but if the bookseller is selling books they are making money
money and why does a bookstore only exist to sell books it is a place of learning where books are
should be places of learning they should also be places of elevation and community and so it is community
to empower a black writer with not only a space as well as support do we get more black writers do you
understand what i'm saying someone said i thought bookstores were for sex but do you understand what i'm
saying and there we go with cassandra harp they're using books they're using learning and empowering as a
front because it is not like i remember when i wanted to do an event at hilltop coffee shop in inglewood
california and the event i wanted to do was called soulful safe space and the context of the event was at the
time i saw that online there was a really big argument happening between folks who were annoyed that gail king
had asked lisa leslie about kobe bryant's history of his rape charges and people who uh were in support
of snoop's response which was some like really desperate disrespectful words to gail so i said let's
create something where people from the community can come and have like actual discourse and
respectful discourse and dialogue and exchange and so i created this space called soulful safe space
and the idea was that there would be a mic on the left and a mic on the right and then seating in the
center and people who are on one side of the argument will line up on this side people who are on other
side of the argument will line up on this side and then the people in the center they would either
participate or not and then me and a guest would moderate my guest at the time was author um who's
my guest i can't even remember who my guest was at the time nonetheless we had a great time however
i had to they charged me to rent the space they charged me to rent the space and i was confused
as to why a black owned coffee shop in inglewood would charge someone to hold a community event in their
space when it wasn't going to require any extra labor on their part again i am not
a massive corporation that's different if mbc wants to come and have a screening i get it but when an
individual wants to hold something of merit in your space for your community why are you charging them
i the the the the bookseller said well we can't count on people coming to the store to buy your book
and also buying books from our store so it doesn't make sense for us to host you now someone here said
we don't charge for community events in our space even though we're struggling because collaboration is
priceless it is and i think that there's a difference between community events there's
a difference between aligning with folks who are actually symbiotic to your business and charging folks
who are just utilizing your space without pouring back into your space you understand what i'm saying
so these are the questions that particularly us who are business owners have to ask ourselves
how are we capitalists and what bridge can we build from the current capitalism to the hopeful and effective
socialism every brick on that bridge is an effective effort towards
solutions and yes zio xo xo xo xyo zenez blabas collabing can also give you more people who want to do
business with you as a customer so these are really important concepts to think about to apply
when we are talking about what needs to happen for change it does not happen simply because it
needs to happen it requires a particular way of thinking when we talk about the no kings rally
and people saying oh you know everybody picking on us for doing this needs to shut up that lets me know
they do not have the necessity the net the necessary way of thinking to make effective change because the
necessary way of thinking to make effective change is going to require curiosity and expanded perspective
okay so your limited perspective without understanding that you're limited that your perspective is limited
will always get in the way of your ability to see beyond you so look out for the link for my one
my one woman shows live stream live from la and book release i look forward to sharing this work
with you i look forward to growing with you i look growing i look forward to he continuing to heal with
you and i look forward to fighting with you alongside you because that's really where we are
we are we are in a time it is the dawning of aquarius i'm taking an astrology class and baby the way uranus
is placed we are in it for seven years so you better get comfortable in battle mode okay
mwah and if you want to see my excitement from when i found the book when it arrived at my house
then please go to my patreon and subscribe it is five dollars um someone said
uh please would love you to come to san francisco
come sell your book at the black and brown social club small not a store please message me
hold on let me screenshot and i will message you thank you queen namas
um i hope everybody has a great evening and um that you put some thought to this question
how are you a capitalist good night